

□ (+61) 410 206 745 | ■ me@michaelmcallister.org | # michaelmcallister.org | □ michaelmcallister | □ mpmcallister

Summary_

An enthusiastic Systems Engineer with almost 10 years of experience designing, building (and troubleshooting!) some of the largest distributed systems in the world. A Linux enthusiast that loves automation and approaching operational problems with software solutions that scale.

As well as my technical skills, I've also delivered numerous presentations, training/mentoring and actively involved as a technical interviewer conducting over one hundred phone and in person interviews.

Skills_

Software Development Python, Bash, Golang, Protocol Buffers, CI/CD

Web JavaScript (ES6, TypeScript), Web Components (Polymer, Lit), LESS, SASS

Systems & Networking Linux, OSPF/BGP, TCP/IP, Routing & Switching (Juniper MX, Cisco NCS), DNS, SQL (Postgres, MySQL, Cloud Spanner)

Cloud AWS: EC2, S3, RDS, VPC, Lambda, GCP: Cloud Spanner, GCS, Stackdriver

Work Experience __

Google Sydney, Australia

Jul. 2018 - PRESENT SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR

· Responsible for the operational upkeep of a globally distributed CDN (Google Global Cache) operating in over 1,300 cities in more than 200 countries and territories powering products such as YouTube

- · Designed and implemented an on-device monitoring solution written in Go for top-of-rack switches that communicates health status via serial output
- · Contributed various bug fixes and features for the public facing Google ISP Portal written in Python, JavaScript and SASS
- · Designed and implemented a sophisticated rules-based ingestion engine in Go that applies routing, priority and auto-remediation decisions to inbound tickets driven by text based configuration
- · Responsible for reporting and metrics (SQL, Dashboarding) of the fleet for metrics such as annualised failure rate for HDDs to ensure a high degree of cache efficiency

Amazon Web Services Sydney, Australia Jul. 2016 - Jun. 2018

SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

- · Scaling, monitoring and fire-fighting the Amazon RDS control plane powering the largest database fleet in the world
- · Designed and built a solution in Java to ingest and analyse alarming data to identify operational trends and patterns
- · Built supporting tools, including a web application in Python to understand and interpret ingested data both in real time and in automated weekly reports to stakeholders (to the GM level)
- · Documented & drove process change that uses this data to influence the cadence and velocity of feature development
- Participate in hiring (100+ interviews) identifying potential in candidates to help fuel Amazon's expansive growth

Amazon Web Services Sydney, Australia

Apr. 2015 - Jul. 2016

CLOUD SUPPORT ENGINEER

- Subject Matter Expert for EC2 Linux tasked with fleet-wide capacity management, and XEN dom0/hypervisor level troubleshooting
- Offered systems architecture advice and troubleshooting to customers using Amazon Web Services (EC2, Route 53, RDS, IAM, VPC, etc.) as solutions for their projects - focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, scalability
- · Facilitated training sessions for new engineers on AWS EBS (Elastic Block Store), as well as advanced troubleshooting for tenured Engineers

iiNet Perth, Australia

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR Aug. 2013 - Mar. 2015

• Part of a 24/7 on call rotation for the infrastructure and supporting services for Australia's #2 ISP (LDAP, DNS, E-Mail, Web Servers)

- · Design, implementation and operational support for iiNet's DNS infrastructure (PowerDNS) that supported over 1 million active services across Australia
- Maintain & document disaster recovery plans, policies and procedures

iiNet Perth, Australia

NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR Aug. 2012 - Aug. 2013

- Proactive monitoring of the availability & performance of iiNet's key systems and applications, including F5 BIG-IP load balancers, *NIX Servers (Linux, Solaris), NetApp Storage Appliances and Juniper networking equipment
- Physical installation, cabling and configuration of servers, and ADSL DSLAMs
- Incident Response & Post Mortem reviews

JUNE 1, 2021 MICHAEL MCALLISTER · RÉSUMÉ

Education

Charles Sturt University

Sydney, Australia

GRADUATE CERTIFICATE IN NETWORK AND SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATION

Jan. 2016 - Jan. 2017

TAFE NSW

Sydney, Australia

ADVANCED DIPLOMA IN SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT

Jan. 2015 - Jan. 2016

Referees

References available upon request.